

Dhilip Kumar Veerapandi

Intern - A*STAR (SimTech)



Professional Expertise

Self-directed and motivated Problem solver with Fluency in Python for data Analysis and NodeJS, Angular, C#, Java for web development.

Experience in building dynamic chatbots with Dialogflow Framework

with additional knowledge of Data Engineering, Machine learning techniques.



Education

2019-01 -2019-02

Graduate Diploma: Systems Analysis

Institute Of Systems Science, National University Of Singapore - Singapore

• Pursuing with 4.25 GPA

2012-01 -2016-01

Bachelor of Engineering: Mechanical Engineering

University College Of Engineering, BIT Campus - TRICHY

- Graduated with 8.13 GPA
- Received Gold medal for academic excellence of holding 1st rank in Department of Mechanical and Automobile studies
- Dean's Honors List Semester-8 Year-2016



Work History

2019-09 -2020-01

Intern

A*STAR - SIMTECH, Singapore, Singapore

1. Designed and Developed Name Card Scanner for



Address

03-149, 352 Clementi Avenue 2.

Singapore, Clementi, 120352

Phone

908-901-77

E-mail

dhilip_kumar@u.nus.edu

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/dhilipbinny

WWW

https://github.com /DhilipBinny

WWW

http://www.dhilip.ml



Database - MY SQL, SQLite, MS SQL, PostgreSQL, Mongo DB, Firebase



Web Development - Html 5, Razor, Thymeleaf, Angular



Very Good

IDE's - Visual Studio, Eclipse, Jupyter Notebook , Visual Studio Code, Colab



Excellent

Frameworks - Python Flask, Spring, ASP.net MVC 5, DialogFlow



Auto Populating Web-form from Images using Python, OpenCv, pytesseract(OCR), spaCy(NLP) and mongoDB.

- Deployed a 3-Tier web application in Aws Ec2 Instance, with Angular Frontend and Flask API Server backed by mongoDB
- Applied regexp to extract website, email, contact numbers. Used Named Entity Recognition module from Spacy NLP to extract Names from raw text, since its impossible to express the rules using Regular expression for names.

URL: http://bit.ly/2rTOlum

2. Built a Real Time Dashboard using Angular and Nodejs for Capturing the Order status processed by a Robotic Arm.

- Demonstrated the Dashboard at ITAP (Industrial) Transformation ASIA-PACIFIC), a leading trade event for Industry 4.0!
- Developed a nodejs based Micro-service to aggregate data from two separate databases

2016-07 -2017-07

Field Officer

INTERNATIONAL TRACTORS LIMITED - SONALIKA, TamilNadu, TamilNadu

 Increased customer retention and satisfaction by closely monitored team member performance and assessing problematic practices



Project Experience

1. [IoT] Developed a Google Assistant voice agent to control the Raspberry Pi IoT LEDS through Voice as well as chat

- App architecture includes 2 python process and Firebase Database
- Python based Dialogflow bot backend is receiving request from user and updates the Firebase Table. Another python client running on RaspberryPi which syncs data with Google Firebase Database. Since Firebase is a Realtime Database, the change event is propagated to the RaspberryPi

Excellent

Cloud - AWS EC2, RDS, Azure Webapp Svc, Heroku



Web Scraping - Selenium, BeautifulSoup



Data Analysis - Numpy, **Pandas**



Data Visualisation -Matplotlib, Seaborn



Machine Learnig - Sklearn



Very Good

Containers - Docker



Very Good



Computer Aided Design -AUTOCAD, CREO 3.0, CATIA, PDMS, ANSYS.



Client which controls the LED bulbs. I managed to overcome challenges involved to setup Https based backend for Dialogflow to route the fulfilment Request. Also, added a simple vanilla HTML,CSS,JS based web frontend for the App

 Please checkout the demonstration video of the App in the following link URL: http://bit.ly/33X0IJE

2. [Hobby] Developed a SG Bus Timings Web App and Chatbot using LTA Datamall API

- I started this app as a web application, with Angular Frontend and Flask Backend which consumes the LTA Datamall Rest API for realtime bus timings given a bus stop code
- Added a telegram chatbot using botogram in Python, which is running in AWS Ec2 Instance
- Also extended the APP with a Dialogflow Voice
 Assistant so that user can say in voice, instead of typing the text in telegram
- During the process of adding more features for this app, managed to extract out duplicate codes and wrote a separate micro-service for common functionalities so that corresponding backends when they need information they will consume the micro-service, rather than duplicating codes
- Deployed URLs:
 - Web APP deployed in Azure WebApp Service [http://bit.ly/35dWOqm]
 - Telegram Chat-bot with bot backend deployed in AWS Ec2 [http://bit.ly/32SNFlx]
 - Dialogflow bot demonstration [http://bit.ly /2pqXh9A]

[School Project] Designed a functional Leave Application Processing System (Java, Spring Boot App and MySQL)

- Developed Leave application System with functionality such as Admin Panel, Manager and Employee Dashboard as a part of GDipSA NUS ISS Program Group Project
- Took Part in different phases such as Design, Implementation and Integration of the APP Development Lifecycle

- Used Version control software Git to solve code conflicts issue when working with with Group of 4 members
- Played a developer role in the team
- 4. [School Project] Developed a Shopping Cart & Tour Booking System (ASP.NET MVC5, MS-SQL)
- Built a Shopping Cart App with ASP.NET MVC5, RAZOR, MS SQL and using OOP paradigm as a part of GDipSA NUS ISS Program Group Project
- Took Part in Design and Implementation of complete SDLC
- Played a Team Leader and Integrator role, in which i set examples coding styles for rest of the team members to follow. Once features are developed i managed to integrate the parts developed by the peers and debug issues as well
- 5. [Multi Container App] Built and Deployed TASK LIST App, a web application integrated with Google Sign-in and Firebase Authentication using Angular, NodeJs and mongoDB.
- Developed multi-container Dockerized
 Application with 3 Containers as follows, Angular
 Frontend Container, Nodejs backend container
 and Mongodb Database container
- Adopted 12 Factor App principles for the Containerized Apps and deployed in Azure WebApp Service URL: http://bit.ly/2QqZrkl
- [Python Data Analysis] Analysed & Visualised
 Amazon_Consumer_Reviews dataset using Pandas,
 Matplotlib, Sklearn
- Loaded the data in CSV format and cleaned it with pandas
- Performed Exploratory Data Analysis using Pandas,
 Matplotlib and seabon Plotting utilities



Certifications

2019-07

Python Programmer DATACAMP URL:http://bit.ly/2QuSCOT

Data Analyst With Python DATACAMP

Data Scientist with Python DATACAMP
URL:http://bit.ly/35hieDn

Python for Everybody COURSERA URL:http://bit.ly
/2rTAjsF

URL:http://bit.ly/2qofB3x